Georgetown Vertical File Index VF.002 VF.002
Stage
Georgetown Vertical File Index
1700-2018
Stage
VF.002
300 Linear feet
Scope and Contents
These files cover all subjects related to Georgetown--social, economic, cultural, recreational, political, and historical.
Related Materials
Also see the Artificial Collection for rare historical items that have been removed from the Vertical Files. Vertical files related to Washington, D.C., history outside of Georgetown are housed in Washingtoniana at the interim location at Van Ness.
- ABC (Alcoholic Beverage Control) Board
- Additions
  General
  (see also Land Grants)
- Beatty and Hawkins Purchaser List
- Deakins, Lee and Casnave 1813
- Aged Womens' Homes
- Air Pollution
- Alleys
- Analostan Island
- Agricultural Activities
- ANCs - Advisory Neighborhood Commissions - 1976-1997
- ANCs - Advisory Neighborhood Commissions - 1998-1999
- ANCs - Advisory Neighborhood Commissions - 2000-
- Animals
- Archaeology
- Architecture
- Arts
  (see also Music)
- Assembly (and other dances)
- Assessments - 18th Century
- Assessments - 1800 - 1900
- Assessments - 20th Century
  (see also Real Estate Sales)
- Assessments - 21st Century
- Authors
- Awards - PCA
- Bicentennial (Georgetown 1751-1951)
- Bicentennial Celebration (Citizen's Association Correspondence)
- Bicycles
- Biographies (of various Georgetowners thru history - brief)
- Blacks - 19th Century
- Blacks - Black Residential Patterns in Georgetown 1860-1900
- Blacks - 1900-1969
- Blacks - 1970s
- Blacks - 1980s
- Blacks - 1990s
- Blacks - 2000s
- Bloggers
- Boathouses
- Boone, Daniel (plaque)
- Bridges - 19th Century
- Bridges - 31st
- Bridges - Aqueduct
- Bridges - Chain
- Bridges - Constitution Avenue (Roosevelt)
- Bridges - Key
- Bridges - M
- Bridges - P
- Bridges - Que
- Bridges - Rock Creek
- Bridges - Three Sisters
- Bridges - Wisconsin
- Burleith
- Businesses - Antiques
- Businesses - Art Galleries/Craft Shops
- Businesses - Banks
- Businesses - Bars (includes under-aged drinking)
  (see also Georgetown University - Students - Drinking Issues)
- Businesses - Beauty Parlors/Barbers/Spas
- Businesses - Book Sellers
- Businesses - Clothing/Dress
- Businesses - Design
- Businesses - Food/Drugs/Liquors
- Businesses - Furniture/Home Furnishings
- Businesses - Gasoline
- Businesses - General
- Businesses - Lodgings
- Businesses - Motion Picture Theaters
- Businesses - Restaurants - General
- Restaurants - not M St or Wisconsin Avenue
- Businesses - Restaurants - not M St or Wisconsin Avenue - A-M
- Businesses - Restaurants - not M St or Wisconsin Avenue - N-Z
- Restaurants - M St east of Wisconsin Avenue
- Businesses - Restaurants - M St east of Wisconsin Avenue - A-M
- Businesses - Restaurants - M St east of Wisconsin Avenue - N-Z
- Restaurants - M St west of Wisconsin Avenue
- Businesses - Restaurants - M St west of Wisconsin Avenue - A-M
- Businesses - Restaurants - M St west of Wisconsin Avenue - N-Z
- Restaurants - Wisconsin Avenue
- Businesses - Restaurants - Wisconsin Avenue - A-L
- Businesses - Restaurants - Wisconsin Avenue - M-Z
- Retail, Misc.
- Businesses - Retail, Misc. - 1930-1959
- Businesses - Retail, Misc. - 1960-1969
- Businesses - Retail, Misc. - 1970-1979
- Businesses - Retail, Misc. - 1980-1999
- Businesses - Retail, Misc. - 2000-
- Businesses - Retail/Service
- Businesses - Shipping
- Businesses Records Guide - Julie Abell
- Call Box Project
- Canals - Alexandria
- Canals - Barges
- Canals - Chesapeake and Ohio (C and O)
- Canals - Description
- Canals - History - General
- Canals - History - General - 1930s
- Canals - 1930s - 1940s
- Canals - 1940s - 1950s
- Canals - 1950s - 1960s
- Canals - 1960s - 1970s
- Canals - 1970s - 1980s
- Canals - 1980s - 1990s
- Canals - 1990s - 2000s
- Canals - Pictures - 1916, 1930-1959
- Canals - Pictures - 1960-1969
- Canals - Pictures - 1970-1979
- Canals - Pictures - 1980-
- Canals - Towpath - 1940-1959
- Canals - Towpath - 1960-1969
- Canals - Towpath - 1970-1979
- Canals - Towpath - 1980-1999
- Canals - Towpath - 2000-
- Chesapeake and Ohio (C and O) Park and Parkway
- Canals - Chesapeake and Ohio (C and O) Park and Parkway - 1930-1949
- Canals - Chesapeake and Ohio (C and O) Park and Parkway - 1950-1959
- Canals - Chesapeake and Ohio (C and O) Park and Parkway - 1960-1979
- Canals - Chesapeake and Ohio (C and O) Park and Parkway - 1980-
- Canals - Maps
- Canals - Potomac
- Cartoons
- Cemeteries - Holy Rood
- Cemeteries - Mt. Zion
- Cemeteries - Oak Hill
- Cemeteries - General
- Cemeteries - Newsletters
- Cemeteries - Others
- Cemeteries - Presbyterian
- Cemeteries - List of Plots
- Cemeteries - Volta Place Playground
- Cemeteries - Union Baptist/Union Burial Ground
- Children
- Christmas
- Churches - Baptist - Alexander Memorial
- Churches - Baptist - First Baptist
- Churches - Baptist - Georgetown Baptist (formerly West Washington Baptist)
- Churches - Baptist - Jerusalem
- Churches - Black
- Churches - Catholic - Epiphany
- Churches - Catholic - Holy Trinity
- Churches - Catholic - General - 1930s-1950s
- Churches - Catholic - General - 1960s
- Churches - Catholic - General - 1970s
- Churches - Catholic - General - 1980s
- Churches - Catholic - General - 1990s
- Churches - Catholic - General - 2000s
- Churches - Catholic - Our Lady of Victory
- Churches - Catholic - St. Stephen Martyr
- Churches - Divine Science
- Churches - Episcopal - Christ
- Churches - Episcopal - 19th Century and General
- Churches - Episcopal - 1900-1940s
- Churches - Episcopal - 1950s-1960s
- Churches - Episcopal - 1970s-1980s
- Churches - Episcopal - 1990s-
- Churches - Episcopal - Episcopal Heritage Center, Christ the King Parish
- Churches - Episcopal - General
- Churches - Episcopal - Grace - 1900-1950s
- Churches - Episcopal - Grace - 1960s
- Churches - Episcopal - Grace - 1970s
- Churches - Episcopal - Grace - 1980s-1990s
- Churches - Episcopal - Grace - 2000s-
- Churches - Episcopal - Grace - St. John's
- Churches - Episcopal - St. John's - Early Years
- Churches - Episcopal - St. John's - 1930s-1940s
- Churches - Episcopal - St. John's - 1950s-1960s
- Churches - Episcopal - St. John's - 1970s
- Churches - Episcopal - St. John's - 1980s
- Churches - Episcopal - St. John's - 1990s
- Churches - Episcopal - St. John's - 2000s
- Churches - Episcopal - General
- Churches - Episcopal - Georgetown Community
- Churches - Episcopal - Georgetown Ministry Center
- Churches - Lutheran
- Churches - Lutheran - Georgetown Lutheran
- Churches - Methodist - General
- Churches - Methodist - Congress Street
- Churches - Methodist - Dumbarton Street
- Churches - Methodist - Mt. Zion
- Churches - Presbyterian
- Churches - Spiritualist - Church of the Two Worlds
- Cicadas
- Citizens Associations
  (see also Societies and Organizations)
- City Council
  (see Wards)
- Civil War
- Cleanup Campaigns
- "Clifton"
  (see Georgetown Heights - "Elverson House")
- Commissioners - DC and Georgetown
- Congressional Act for Formation of "Old Georgetown," 9/22/1950
- Craftsmen (in antebellum Georgetown)
- Crime and Police - 19th Century
- Crime and Police - 1910s
- Crime and Police - 1920s
- Crime and Police - 1930s
- Crime and Police - 1950s
- Crime and Police - 1960s
- Crime and Police - 1970s
- Crime and Police - 1980s
- Crime and Police - 1990s
- Crime and Police - Starbucks Slayings
- Crime and Police - 2000s
- Customs House
  (see also Post Office)
- Deeds
- Diplomatic Corps.
- Drugs
- Dumbarton House
- Dumbarton Oaks - Conference, 1944
- Dumbarton Oaks - Gardens
- Dumbarton Oaks - Museum and Research Center
- Dumbarton Oaks - Music
- Dumbarton Oaks - Park
- Dumbarton Oaks - Published Materials
- Easements - 18th Century Buildings
- Elderly
- Elections 2000 -
- "Elverson House"
- Embassies
- Ethnic Groups
- Ferry
- Films - "Exorcist"
- Fine Arts Commission
- Fire Dept.
- Fire Marks
- Fires
- Flea Markets - Georgetown
  (see also Safeway)
- Flour Mill
- "Forrest Hall"
- Forts
- Freeway
- Garden Tours - 1960s
- Garden Tours - 2000s
- Gays
- Georgetown - 1890s
- Georgetown - 1900s
- Georgetown - 1910s
- Georgetown - 1920s
- Georgetown - 1930s
- Georgetown - 1940s
- Georgetown - 1950s
- Georgetown - 1960s
- Georgetown - 1970s
- Georgetown - 1980s
- Georgetown - 1990s
- Georgetown - 2000s
- Georgetown Boundaries
- Georgetown - Chronology
- Georgetown Guide Books
- Georgetown Heights - "Elverson House"
- Georgetown Misc.
- Georgetown Name Origin
- Georgetown Park (shopping mall)
- Georgetown 250th Anniversary Celebration (2001)
- Georgetown University - Alumni
- Georgetown University - The Arts
- Georgetown University - Athletics
- Georgetown University - Bicentennial
- Georgetown University - Buildings
- Georgetown University - "Campus Plan 1983 - 2000 and Beyond"
- Georgetown University - Campus Plan 2000 -
- Georgetown University - Canal Road Access
- Georgetown University - Directors - Faculty
- Georgetown University - Dormitories/Housing Issues
- Georgetown University - Electrical Co. Generator - Power Plant
- Georgetown University - Funding
- Georgetown University - History - 19th century
- Georgetown University - History - 1930s
- Georgetown University - History - 1940s
- Georgetown University - History - 1950s
- Georgetown University - History - 1960s
- Georgetown University - History - 1970s
- Georgetown University - History - 1980s
- Georgetown University - History - 1990s
- Georgetown University - History - 2000s
- Georgetown University - Hospital/ Medical Center
- Georgetown University - Hospital 2000-
- Georgetown University - Libraries
- Georgetown University - Medical, Dental and Nursing Schools
- Georgetown University - Public Relations
- Georgetown University - ROTC
- Georgetown University - Sesquicentennial, 1939 and 175th, 1964
- Georgetown University - Students
- Georgetown University - Students - Drinking Issues
  (see also Businesses - Bars)
- Ghosts
- Glover Park
- "Glover Park Gazette"
- Graffiti
- Gunpowder
- HABS - Historic American Buildings Survey
- Halloween
- Harbor
- Health
- Heraldry
- Historic Georgetown Foundation
- Historic Georgetown Inc.
- Historic Preservation - Dept. of Consumer and Regulatory Affairs
- Holidays - Christmas
- Holidays - Halloween
- Holidays - Mothers' Day
- Homelessness
  (see also Shelters)
- Hopfenmaier (rendering plant, aka slaughter house)
- House Tours
  (individual VFs for most years starting with 1927)
- House Tours People
- Humanities Council, DC
- Indians
- Industrial
- Insurance
- Jewish
  (see also Synagogues - Kesher Israel Congregation)
- Key Mansion
- "Key of all Keys"
- "King and I" (connection to Georgetown)
- Lamp Lighters
- Land Grants
- Landmarks
- Legislation
- Library - Columbian
- Library - DC - undated
- Library - DC - broken out by decade
- Library - Georgetown - misc. undated
- Library - Georgetown - broken out by most individual years 1932 to date
- Library - Peabody Association
- Library - Peabody Room - undated histories
- Library - Peabody Room - broken out by most individual years 1936 to date Lime Kilns
- Lincoln
- Litter
  (see Cleanup Campaigns)
- Lottery
- Magazines
- Maps
  Published by Business and Professional Assoc.
- Markets - Georgetown pre 1960
- Markets - Georgetown pre 1960 - 1960s
- Markets - Georgetown pre 1960 - 1970s
- Markets - Georgetown pre 1960 - 1980s
- Markets - Georgetown pre 1960 - 1990s
- Georgetown Market 1970s legal documents - see archival collection
- Masons
- Metro Myth
- Military School
- Militia 1815
- Montgomery County 1776
- Motion Pictures
  (see Films)
- Music
- Navy Registers 1835 and 1842
- Neighborhood Names
- Newspapers - Courant
- Newspapers - Georgetowner
- Newspapers - Holdings
- Newspapers - Misc.
- Newspapers - Times and Patowmack Packet
- Nicknames (Georgetown)
- "Normanstone"
- "Old Georgetown" - Articles
- "Old Georgetown" - Chronology
- "Old Georgetown" - Early 20th Century
- "Old Georgetown" - Especially pre-1895
- "Old Georgetown" - Houses
- "Old Georgetown" - Maps
- "Old Georgetown" - Old Georgetown in Peabody Room, 1951
- "Old Georgetown" - Williams (Mathilde) and Lyle (Robert) Articles
- Old Stone House
- Orphans
- Paper Mill
- Parking - 1940s
- Parking - 1950s
- Parking - 1960s
- Parking - 1970s
- Parking - 1980s
- Parking - 1990s
- Parking - 2000s
- Parks - Book Hill
- Parks - Dumbarton Oaks
- Parks - Francis Scott Key - 1980s
- Parks - Francis Scott Key - 1990s
- Parks - Francis Scott Key - 2000s
- Parks - Misc.
- Parks - Montrose
- Parks - Rock Creek
- Parks - Rose
- Parks - Volta
- Parks - Waterfront Pedestrians
- Police
  (see Crime and Police)
- Population - Pre 1950
- Population - 1950s
- Population - 1970s
- Population - 1980s
- Population - 1990s
- Post Office - Georgetown
  (see also Customs House)
- Post Office - Georgetown - 18th century
- Potomac River - Accidents
- Potomac River - Description
- Potomac River - Ecology
- Potomac River - Floods
- Potomac River - Floods of 1985 and 1996
- Potomac River - History
- Potomac River - 19th century
- Potomac River - Parks
- Potomac River - Potomac River Heritage Partnership
- Potomac River - Pollution
- Potomac River - Sports
- Preservation - 1920s
- Preservation - 1930s
- Preservation - 1940s
- Preservation - 1950s
- Preservation - 1960s
- Preservation - 1970s
- Preservation - 1980s
- Preservation - 1990s
- Preservation - 2000s
- "Pretty Prospects" - Pricilla McNeil
- Protests - May Day 1971
- Public Transportation
- Pumpkins
- Railroads - Baltimore and Ohio
  (see also Railroads, Street Railways, Subways in Georgetown)
- Rats
- Real Estate Sales
- Recreation Centers
  (see also Parks)
- Recreation Guide
- Reminiscences
- Rent Issues
- Residential Sales - 2001
- Rock Creek
- "Rock of Dumbarton" - Pricilla McNeil
- Running Races
- Safeway
  (see also Flea Markets)
- Schools - Private Schools in Georgetown
- Schools - Private Schools in Georgetown - 1795-1845
- Schools - Private Schools in Georgetown - 19th century Ephemera
- Schools - Private Schools in Georgetown - Early
- Schools - Private Schools in Georgetown - Female Seminary
- Schools - Private Schools in Georgetown - Georgetown School of Science and Art
- Schools - Private Schools in Georgetown - Holy Trinity Grade School
- Schools - Private Schools in Georgetown - Industrial Home School
- Schools - Private Schools in Georgetown - Linthicum Institute
- Schools - Private Schools in Georgetown - Visitation Convent and School
- Schools - Private Schools in Georgetown - 1930-1969
- Schools - Private Schools in Georgetown - 1970-1999
- Schools - Private Schools in Georgetown - 1993-1995 (fire)
- Schools - Private Schools in Georgetown - 2000-
- Schools - Private Schools in Georgetown - Printed matter 1 of 2
- Schools - Private Schools in Georgetown - Printed matter 2 of 2
- Schools - Private Schools in Georgetown - Washington International School/ International Bilingual Primary
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Addison
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Chamberlain
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Corcoran
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Curtis
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Duke Ellington High School
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Fillmore
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - General and Misc.
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Gordon
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Hardy
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Jackson
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Phillips
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Stoddert
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Threlkeld
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Western High School - 1920s and earlier
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Western High School - 1930s
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Western High School - 1940s
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Western High School - 1950s
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Western High School - 1960s
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Western High School - 1970s
- Schools -Public Schools in Georgetown - Wormley
- Scissors Grinders
- Seniors
- Sewers
- Shelter
  (see also Homelessness)
- Sidewalks - Sewer Caps
- Signage
- Slavery
- "Slip"
- Social Conditions
- Social List (Green Book)
- Societies and Organizations - Association of the Oldest Inhabitants of D.C.
  (see also Citizens Associations)
- Societies and Organizations - Business Improvement District (B.I.D.)
- Societies and Organizations - Boy Scouts
- Societies and Organizations - Boys and Girls Club - 1930s
- Societies and Organizations - Boys and Girls Club - 1940s
- Societies and Organizations - Boys and Girls Club - 1950s
- Societies and Organizations - Boys and Girls Club - 1960s
- Societies and Organizations - Boys and Girls Club - 1970s
- Societies and Organizations - Boys and Girls Club - 1980s
- Societies and Organizations - Boys and Girls Club - 2000s
- Societies and Organizations - Burleith Citizens Association
- Societies and Organizations - Burleith Citizens Association Newsletter
- Societies and Organizations - Business and Professional Association of Georgetown
- Societies and Organizations - Citizens Association of Georgetown (C.A.G.) - 1970s
- Societies and Organizations - Citizens Association of Georgetown (C.A.G.) - 2007-
- Societies and Organizations - Citizens Association of Georgetown (C.A.G.) - 2000-2006
- Societies and Organizations - Citizens Association of Georgetown (C.A.G.) - Newsletters 12/2000-
- Societies and Organizations - Federation of Citizens Association DC
- Societies and Organizations - Foundation for Historic Georgetown
- Societies and Organizations - Foundation for Historic Georgetown Easements and Application
- Societies and Organizations - Forms
- Societies and Organizations - Georgetown Business Property Owners Association (1962-63)
- Societies and Organizations - Georgetown Canal and Riverside Council - 1960s
- Societies and Organizations - Georgetown Canal and Riverside Council - 1970s
- Societies and Organizations - Georgetown Children's House
- Societies and Organizations - Georgetown Children's House Newsletter (1938-40)
- Societies and Organizations - Georgetown Citizens Association 1930s-1950s
- Societies and Organizations - Georgetown Garden Club
- Societies and Organizations - Georgetown Heritage Trust (previously Historic Georgetown Foundation)
- Societies and Organizations - Historic Georgetown Inc.
- Societies and Organizations - Junior Army-Navy Guild Assoc.
- Societies and Organizations - Kiwanis
- Societies and Organizations - Lions Club
- Societies and Organizations - Neighborhood House
- Societies and Organizations - Progressive Citizens Association of Georgetown
- Societies and Organizations - Rock Creek Citizens Association (Black)
- Spite Houses
- Streams
- Street Lights
- Street Railways - 1860s
  (see also Public Transportation, Railroads, Subway in Georgetown)
- Street Railways - 1870s
- Street Railways - 1880s
- Street Railways - 1890s
- Street Railways - 1910s
- Street Railways - 1930s
- Street Railways - 1950s
- Street Railways - 1960s
- Street Railways - 1970s
- Street Railways - 1980s
- Street Railways - 1990s
- Street Railways - 2000s
- Streets - 1790s
- Streets - 1810s
- Streets - 1850s
- Streets - 1860s
- Streets - 1870s
- Streets - 1880s
- Streets - 1930s
- Streets - 1940s
- Streets - 1950s
- Streets - 1960s
- Streets - 1970s
- Streets - 1980s
- Streets - 1990s
- Streets - 2000s
- Subway in Georgetown
  (see also Public Transportation, Railroads, (see also Public Transportation, Railroads, Street Railways)
- Surplus Property
- Suter's Tavern
- Synagogues - Kesher Israel Congregation
- Taverns
- Tax Sale: 1825
- Taxes: Special Wartime Tax
- Telephones
- Television
- Television Shows
- Terrorism - 9/11/2001 Remembrance
- Tobacco
- Tour Guides
- Tourism
- Traffic
- Trees
- Tudor Place
  (see House History File - 1644 31st Street, NW)
- Tunnels
- Utilities - Georgetown Gas Light Co. (1919)
- Utilities - Manhole Cover Blasts 2000 - 2003
- Volta Bureau
- Walking Tours
- Wards
- Washington Harbor
- Waterfront - 1960s and earlier
- Waterfront - 1970s
- Waterfront Inventory - 1972?
- Waterfront Inventory - 1972? - 1980s
- Waterfront Inventory - 1972? - 1990s
- Waterfront Inventory - 1972? - 2000s
- Water Supply
- Whitehurst Freeway - 1930s
- Whitehurst Freeway - 1940s
- Whitehurst Freeway - 1950s
- Whitehurst Freeway - 1960s
- Whitehurst Freeway - 1970s
- Whitehurst Freeway - 1980s
- Whitehurst Freeway - 1990s
- Whitehurst Freeway - 2000s
- World War II
- Writers Who Lived in Georgetown
- Youth - 1930s and 1940s
  (see also Parks, Recreation Centers)
- Youth - 1950s to 1970s
- Zoning